A Guide to the Sterling Farm (Loudoun County, Va.) Records, 1909-1952
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Sterling Farm (Loudoun County, Va.) Records, 1909-1952
The Library of Virginia
50967
.45 cubic feet (1 box)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Historical Information
Sterling Farm was a cattle and dairy business located in Loudoun County, Virginia. It was purchased in 1909 by journalist and academic Dr. Albert Shaw (1857-1947). It originally contained 1640 acres. It was called "The Experimental Farm," for Shaw was the first area farmer to receive a federal grant for applying "scientific methods" to the raising of crops and livestock. In 1938, Shaw gifted the farm to his son, Albert Shaw, Jr. (1897-1983). The farm was later purchased from the younger Shaw by its manager, Fred F. Tavenner (1905-1979).
Scope and Content
Records, 1909-1952, of Sterling Farm, a cattle and dairy business in Loudoun County, Virginia, owned by journalist Dr. Albert Shaw (1857-1947), and later his son Albert Shaw, Jr. (1897-1983) of New York, and managed by Fred F. Tavenner (1905-1979). The collection includes an agreement and certificate of partnership, correspondence, deeds, financial statements, photographs, and a history of the farm. The majority of the letters are between Dr. Shaw, who was residing in Winter Park, Florida and Tavenner, and concern farming activities, business matters, maintenance and upkeep, and expenses, as well as weather, health, social activities, family news, trips, and visits. The financial statements contain expenses and receipts, assests and liabilities, and payroll records which include employee names and salaries.
Contents List
- Agreement and Partnership, 1951-1952. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Breeder's Gazette, (December 1941). (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1909-1913. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1937. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1938. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1940. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1941. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1942. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1943. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1944. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1945. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, undated. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Dairy Barn Plan, 1940. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Deeds. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Financial Statements, 1939. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Financial Statements, 1940. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Financial Statements, 1941. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Financial Statements, 1942. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Financial Statements, 1943. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Financial Statements, 1944. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Financial Statements, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Photographs - Buildings. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Photographs - Corn Planting. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Photographs - Land and Livestock. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Photographs - People. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "Putting the Soil to Bed for the Winter" by Drs. Carl Bender and Firman Baer. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "The Story of Sterling Farm" by Albert Shaw, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 29)